When you're coding, it's tempting to try writing a program that does everything.
عندما تقوم بالتكويد، سيشجعك ذلك على محاولة كتابة برنامج يقوم بكل شيء.
Typically, you'll be coding something that you thought was simple,
ونموذجيًا، ستكوّد شيئًا ما اعتقدت أنه بسيط،
and then a new idea arises.
ثم تظهر لك فكرة جديدة.
You slide it right in,
تقوم بسحبها هنا،
because it makes sense to you here and now.
لأن ذلك منطقي بالنسبة لك هنا الآن.
Before you know it, your code ends up very long,
قبل أن تتعرف إليها، يكود الكود طويلا،
quite complicated, and basically impossible to debug.
معقد جدًا ويستحيل تتبع أخطاءه.
You really don't want such a big code block.
إنك حقًا لا ترغب في كتلة كود كبيرة هذه.
Your program might be full of clever ideas and slick implementation,
من المحتمل أن يكون برنامجك ذاخرًا بالأفكار الذكية وعمليات التنفيذ المصقولة،
but it's impossible to read and you simply can't
ولكن تستحيل القراءة ولا تستطيع ببساطة
reuse all that great code somewhere else.
أن تعيد استخدام هذا الكود العظيم كله في مكان آخر.
This is why it's important to plan your ideas before you start coding.
ولذلك فهو أمر هام أن تخطط لأفكارك قبل البدء في التكويد.
That one great idea you're trying to implement,
إن هذه الفكرة العظيمة التي تحاول تنفيذها،
it's almost certainly got several parts, multiple steps,
قد حظيت بالعديد من الاجزاء، والخطوات
or different cases that can be split apart,
أو الحالات المختلفة التي يمكن أن تنشطر،
worked on, and put back together again.
تعمل عليها وتعيدها معًا من جديد.
Thinking about the pieces of the problem you're solving before
بالتفكير في أجزاء المشكلة التي حللتها من قبل
your fingers even touch the keyboard means you can lay plans,
ستلامس أصابعك لوحة الكتابة مما يعني أنك باستطاعتك إلقاء خططك،
split up the work, and plan how to test your code early on.
شطر أعمالك وتخطيط كيفية اختبار كودك مبكرًا.
Let's try an example.
لنحاول باستخدام مثال.